Abhigith Neil Abraham

Puthenkandathil house, Manakkappady, Karumalloor P.O, Aluva, Ernakulam, Kerala, India, 683511

📕+91.7907752461 | 💌 abhijithneilabrahampk@gmail.com | 🖸 github.com/abhijithneilabraham | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/abhijith-neil-abraham-765165141/

Personal Profile

Software Engineer with 3 years of experience in Full stack development, Machine Learning Research, ML software, DevOps, and Open Source. I have worked on a wide variety of useful projects for multiple organisations and is passionate about contributing to Open Source for better future of software development. I have also taken responsibility for building and scaling many projects which found their way into production. I aspire to work in a community-like workplace where greatness is achieved.

Education

College of Engineering, Trivandrum

Trivandrum, India

BTech in Electrical and Electronics

August 2016 - June 2020

Graduated with 8.1 CGPA on a scale of 10

Work Experience _

Aecmaster.com Remote

Full Stack and AI Research Engineer

March 15 - Present

- Led a 5-month project to integrate ChatGPT into the AEC ecosystem to understand AEC data more efficiently for customers.
- Built full stack solution make a version control alternative for AEC data that also included 3D renderings using Threejs for building models.
- Developed a Chrome extension for optimized data handling in ChatGPT and a real-time platform for AEC data visualization.

Autonomio Helsinki, Finland

Machine Learning Engineer

July 2022 - Present

- · Authored and Open Sourced Jako, a distributed computing tool for hyperparameter optimisation using multiple machines. Responsible for building, testing and writing documentation.
- · Authored and Open sourced EasyEnergy, a tool to track carbon emissions and energy draw for Machine Learning Experiments. Responsible for the idea, roadmap, building, testing and documentation.

Chennai, India Saama

Machine Learning Research Engineer

Dec 2020 - June 2022

- · Worked with the Research team for innovating impact of machine learning with natural language processing in Clinical Domain.
- Wrote Research papers for NLP tasks such as Bio Sentence Transformers
- · Worked with internal software research team to build tools to automate cross matching of medical domain databases.

Minicog

Freelance Machine Learning Engineer

Kochi, India May 2020 - Dec 2020

- Built an open source tool named TableQA for querying natural language on tabular data.
- Wrote a research paper on TableQA.

Research Publications

- Research paper BioSimCSE: BioMedical Sentence Embeddings using Contrastive learning
- Research paper TableQuery: Querying tabular data with natural language
- Research Journal Deep Learning Applications with Python

Skills

Technical Skills

Python (Tensorflow, PyTorch, Pandas, Scikit-learn), SQL, Postgres, Docker, Git, Vue.js, AWS, GCP, Ubuntu Linux, Real-time Data Analytics, Three.js, Linux tools, Apt, Scripting, &TFX, Tableau, Firebase, Hasura, Metabase

Soft Skills

Community Management, People Relationship, Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation, Engaging Presentation, Leadership, Communication, Logical Thinking, Project Management, Team Coordination, Strategic Planning

Languages

English Professional proficiency Hindi Professional proficiency Malayalam Native proficiency

AUGUST 31, 2023